ppi2pass.com 2019-02-16

# Privacy

* * *

Welcome to PPI and ppi2pass.com website (“Website”). Professional Publications, Inc. d/b/a PPI (“PPI”), values your business and loyalty. We are committed to the protection of subscriber and customer privacy. PPI has created this Privacy Policy in order to demonstrate its commitment to the privacy and protection of your personal information. To better protect your privacy, PPI provides this notice explaining our information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used in connection with our PPI services.

BY USING THIS WEBSITE, YOU SIGNIFY YOUR AGREEMENT TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY.  WE MAY AMEND THIS PRIVACY POLICY AT ANY TIME.  IF WE MAKE A MATERIAL CHANGE TO THE WAY IN WHICH WE COLLECT, USE, AND/OR DISCLOSE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION, WE WILL POST A NOTICE ON THIS WEBSITE.

**Information about Us**

Our Services and Website our operated by Professional Publications, Inc., 1250 Fifth Avenue, Belmont, CA, 94002 (under the business name of “PPI”).  Click [**here**](https://ppi2pass.com/contact-us) if you would like to contact us.

**Privacy Officer**

Our Company Privacy Officer is our General Counsel, who can be reached at PPI, 1250 Fifth Avenue, Belmont, CA, 94002, Attn: Privacy Officer. 

**1\. What Information Is Collected**

The following are the types of information we may collect:

**Personal Information**

PPI may collect personal information (“Personal Information”), which shall include but is not limited to, name, telephone number, email address, home or business mailing address, exam registration information, and details regarding your mode of payment (e.g., credit/debit card or account information) when you access certain areas of the Website that require registration or payment for products and services, or if you require more information about those services.

**Non-Personal Information**

At other times, PPI may collect information that cannot be used to directly identify you (“Non-Personal Information” and together with Personal Information, “Information”), such as browser type, Dynamic Internet Protocol (IP) address, “click stream” data, and similar non-personally identifiable information.  For example, we may aggregate Non-Personal Information about you and other customers who visit certain areas of our Website. Aggregated information will not contain any information that can be linked directly back to you.

**Electronic Communications**

When you open emails from us or navigate our Site, we may log and store such information. We may also keep records of various communications regarding the types of products and services that you indicate are of interest to you via your response to email and text messaging. You will always have the option to opt-out of such communications by clicking the “unsubscribe” link in an email or contacting PPI directly and requesting your information be removed.

While we take all reasonable steps to protect the privacy of our Website visitors, we cannot promise that the current limitations of our online applications programming will address every browser setting or honor every personal browser preference.

Further, our online service providers or business partners may implement technologies that allow for the collection of personally identifiable information over time and across Websites. We recommend that you review each privacy policy posted on the Websites that you visit to better understand privacy practices on those Websites.

**2\. How Do We Collect Information**

We may collect Information from you in several different areas on the Website, including, without limitation, those described below:

**Registration**

You will be asked to complete a registration form and provide Personal Information.  You will be asked to choose a user ID and password in order to access your subscription, as well as to take advantage of certain features on the Website or digital messaging services, such as newsletters, email or contests. You will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose Personal Information to us and what communications you would like to receive; however, please be advised that many products and services available on the Website require registration and if you elect not to provide such information, you will not be able to take advantage of those products and services.

**Contests or Sweepstakes**

We may periodically operate contests and sweepstakes through the Website and messaging services that will require registration or the submission of Personal Information. This Information may be used to contact you for winner notification, prize delivery confirmation or other related purposes (see the rules of each contest for details about how your Personal Information will be used, including postings to the Website).

**Surveys and Games**

From time-to-time we may request Personal Information from you in conjunction with a survey or games, such as quizzes. Participation is voluntary, and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose Personal Information to the Website. At times, you may have to register to vote or to take part in a survey. When you register to play games on our Website, you may be asked to provide Personal Information.

**Transaction Information**

If you conduct a financial transaction on the Website, such as subscribing to PPI or order other products/services offered on the Website, we will ask you to complete an order form that will request certain Personal Information from you, including contact information, demographic information, credit card and other financial information. Even though the collection form may have the look and feel of ppi2pass.com, please be aware you will be giving your Personal Information to our and your authorized payment processors (such as credit card service processors) and to third party Internet Service Providers, and that in some instances the Privacy Policies of those third party Internet Service Providers will govern the collection of your Personal Information. As discussed in more detail in Section 6 of this Privacy Policy, please reference the privacy policies available from these pages for any privacy related concerns.

**Cookies and Tracking Technology**

We may use any number of tools to collect Non-Personal Information about you, your computer access points, and the web browser that you use to connect to our Website. For example, “cookies” are tiny text files that we place on your computer’s hard drive when you visit our Website. We may use cookies to personalize your Website experience. You do not have to accept our cookies and you may delete them after they have been placed on your hard drive. If you do not accept or delete our cookies, some areas of our Website that you access may take more time to work, or may not function properly. For more information about cookies, visit: http://www.allaboutcookies.org.

PPI may also collect additional Non-Personal Information from your web browser each time you visit our Website. We may collect Information on the pages that you visit, the promotions or advertisements that you click on, the courses you watch, and other actions that you take while using our Website. This information may include your IP address, the type of browser, the time that your browser was used to access our Website, and the referring Website address.

Our Internet Service Providers (defined below) and supporting service platform providers may also use other standard web-based technologies to analyze your movements while accessing our Website. The technologies may include analytic solutions, web “beacons,” “pixel tags,” and “clear gifs.” These technologies help us ascertain the effectiveness of our product and service campaigns and marketing programs, allow us to customize the services offered on or through our Website, and help determine the best use for Website content, and product and service offerings. Some of this information, including the IP address, may be stored on our Internet service provider’s server logs, and may be available for extended periods of time.

**3\. How Your Information Is Used**

PPI and its partners may use your Personal Information and/or Non-Personal Information for the following purposes:

  * ■  Confirm and enable your subscription;
  * ■  Carry out obligations arising from any contract entered into between you and us and to provide you with information, products and services;
  * ■  Determine your general geographic location and internet service provider to enable us to quickly and efficiently respond to inquiries and requests;
  * ■  Complete financial or other transactions that you have requested;
  * ■  Communicate with you about your account or transactions with us, including order confirmation from us or your designated payment processor;
  * ■  Send you information regarding changes to our policies;

  *     □    Personalize content and experiences on our Websites;
  *     □    Provide you with advertising based on your activity on our Websites and applications and on third party sites and applications;
  *     □    Send you articles of interest on the subjects covered by our courses;
  *     □    Send you e-mail surveys to vote for the products you want us to offer, to rate the quality of our service or individual products, and to tell us what improvements to make to our services;

  * ■  Optimize or improve our products, services and operations;
  * ■  Detect, investigate and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal and

  *     □    Send you offers and promotions for PPI products and services, or third-party products and services.

PPI uses the services of independent companies to provide certain services to you, including, without limitation, Website hosting services, course content distribution services, credit and debit card processing, mobile application providers, order fulfilment, and Internet connectivity services (“Internet Service Providers”) in connection with PPI.  We may share your Non-Personal and Personal Information with these third parties as necessary to provide these services to you.

We use your Personal Information to send you order confirmations. In such cases, you should receive via e-mail an order confirmation after placing your order.  You may also receive confirmation e-mails from your designated payment processor.  Occasionally, you will receive articles of interest on the subjects covered by our Service or courses. From time-to-time you may receive e-mail surveys to vote for changes you want us to make, to rate the quality of PPI service or individual products, and to tell us what improvements to make to PPI and our services. We may also use your Personal Information to notify you of special offers. You may receive e-mails notifying you when products or services go on sale. These e-mails also make ordering extremely simple—if you see products or services that interest you, simply click on the links in the e-mail to find out more.

We may also use your IP address to help protect us and our Internet Service Providers from fraud. Additional uses of your Non-Personal and Personal Information will allow us to tailor products and services specific to your needs, to help organize and manage your customer relationship and our business, to conduct business, to provide you with customer and member support, to perform functions that are described to you at the time of collection, and to enforce our Website’s Terms of Use.

We may also use Non-Personal aggregate information to improve our Website. For example, our Internet Service Providers may report to us that there were a particular number of visitors to a certain area of our Website, or that a certain number of men or a certain number of women completed our registration form in particular areas of our Website. Such information may also be used to analyze the effectiveness of our business and advertising models.

**4\. Shared Information**

We may disclose or share your Personal Information with the Internet Service Providers as appropriate.  We may also disclose your Personal Information as is necessary to: (a) comply with a subpoena or court order; (b) cooperate with law enforcement or other government agency; (c) establish or exercise our legal rights; (d) protect the property or safety of our company and employees, contractors, vendors, and suppliers; (e) defend against legal claims; (f) help with internal and external investigations; or (g) as otherwise required by law or permitted by law. We may disclose your information in connection with the sale or merger of PPI or any transaction that involves the sale or assignment of some or all of our assets.

We use third-party ad serving, analytics, and audience and traffic measurement services.   We may use a third-party network advertiser to serve the advertisements on the Website or may use a traffic measurement service to analyze the traffic on the Website or the use of our Services. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your visits to this Website and other Websites you have visited. Third-party ad serving enables us to target advertisements to you for products or Websites you might be interested in.  Audience and traffic measurement services allow us to collect anonymous traffic and behavior information from the Website by monitoring anonymous visitor activity. Although advertisers or other companies do not have access to the Website cookies, the Website's advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may themselves set and access their own cookies on your computer if you choose to have your cookies enabled in your browser. Cookies allow third-party advertisers to show you advertisements or content you might be interested in. Note that any images (or any other parts of a web page) served by third parties in association with third-party cookies may serve as web beacons, which enable third parties to carry out the previously described activities. Other companies' uses of their cookies are subject to their own privacy policies, not this one. Please visit http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp in order to learn more about the information collection practices and "opt-out" procedures of third-party ad servers we may use.

Under the California “Shine the Light” law, California residents may opt-out of PPI’s disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. As detailed below, you may choose to opt-out of the sharing of your personal information with third parties for marketing purposes at any time by contacting us.      

With regard to name and postal address only, from time to time, we may make our mailing list available to carefully screened companies. If you prefer we don’t disclose your name and postal address, please call our Customer Sales Support team at 1-650-593-9119, email [ info@ppi2pass.com](mailto:info@ppi2pass.com), or write to us at PPI, 1250 Fifth Avenue, Belmont, CA, 94002, Attn: Privacy Policy.

**5\. Links To Third-party Websites**

Links from this Website may allow you to directly access Websites operated by third parties, including, without limitation, our service providers or marketing partners. And, you may be able to access this Website or your PPI subscription content through third parties, including App providers, with whom we have marketing relationships.  Some of these third-party marketing channels may be “co-branded” with our logo; however, note that these third-party channels are not operated, controlled or maintained by PPI. These channels or links are provided for your convenience only and should be used with your discretion and prudent judgment. Links from our Website to third-party Websites do not constitute sponsorship, endorsement, or approval of the content, policies or practices of such third-party Websites. The collection and use of your information by such third parties is the responsibility of the third parties, and they may use your personal information as described in their own privacy policies and terms of use.  We are not responsible for any information these Websites, Apps or digital channels may obtain and we do not oversee their policies or practices. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information provided to or gathered by the third parties that operate them. The privacy policies of these third-party Websites and Apps may differ from ours. These Websites and Apps may ask you for Personal Information. Please review the privacy policy on third-party channels before submitting information, because we do not have control over the use of information collected on these Websites or Apps.

**6\. Information Security**

PPI makes reasonable efforts to ensure that our Internet Service Providers and any other person to whom we disclose your Personal Information to have implemented physical, electronic, and procedural security measures to assist with safeguarding your Personal Information, and to help protect against unauthorized access and disclosure. We use contracts and other measures with our service providers to maintain the confidentiality and security of your Personal Information and to prevent such Personal Information from being used for any other purpose.        

PPI, our Internet Service Providers and other persons to whom we disclose Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy, may perform activities outside of the United States. As a result, your Personal Information may be used, stored and/or accessed in countries outside of the United States. However, all such Personal Information will be protected in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Please note that when your Personal Information is located outside of the United States it will be subject to the laws of the country in which it is situated.     

Notwithstanding our efforts, the Internet and online services have inherent security risks. PPI cannot promise, and you should not expect, that your Personal Information, personal searches, and other communications will always remain secure. You should take care with regard to how you handle and disclose your Personal Information or any username or password that you are required to use to access services on the Website or online service.

**7\. Data Retention Periods**

We will retain your Personal Information as needed to provide you services and for our own records. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you Services contact us at [ info@ppi2pass.com](mailto:info@ppi2pass.com). We will retain and use your Information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**8\. Keeping Your Information Updated**

We take care to keep the Personal Information in our records as accurate, complete and up to date as necessary for the purposes for which it is used. However, we also rely on you to tell us when your Personal Information changes. You may update and correct as necessary your personal information by contacting us using our contact information in the “How to Contact Us” section below.

**9\. Other Social Media Websites, Blogs, Message Boards**

The Website and PPI Mobile Applications may make chat rooms, forums, commenting and message boards available to you and other users. You are not required to provide any Personal Information when using these areas but you may choose to do so. If you post Personal Information online, it will be publicly available and you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties. In addition, when you post a comment, the user name with which you registered for the Website and your current location may be made publicly available on the Website and through PPI Mobile applications. By using the commenting features of the Website and PPI Mobile applications, you acknowledge that your user name and location information will be disclosed. We cannot ensure the security of any information you choose to make public in a chat room, forum, or message board. Also, we cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose Personal Information in these areas. To request removal of your Personal Information from our Website, blog or community forum, contact us at: [ info@ppi2pass.com](mailto:info@ppi2pass.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personal Information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**10\. General Audience Website Not Directed Toward Children**

This Website is a general audience Website. Our content is neither directed toward minors nor children who are under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of 13. If PPI or our Internet Service Providers become aware that a minor or a child under the age of 13 has provided us with Personal Information without the parental consent, that information will be deleted from our databases. Parents who have questions about Personal Information that may have been submitted by a child under the age of 13 should email us at: [ info@ppi2pass.com](mailto:info@ppi2pass.com)

**11\. Consent to Privacy Policy**

By using this Website or PPI Service, you signify your agreement to the terms of this Privacy Policy. We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will post a notice on the Website and/or send an email to users who have provided an email address. Please note that you should always update your personal information to provide us with a current email address.

**12\. Access to Personal Information and Privacy Concerns**

You have the right to access personal information we hold about you and to have any concerns you may have over our policies and practices addressed. In addition, you have the right to obtain information regarding our policies and practices with respect to our use of service providers outside United States. To access your information, discuss your concerns or learn more about our policies and practices please see our contact information in the “How to Contact Us” section below.;

**13\. Questions About This Privacy Policy**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the privacy practices of this Website, please contact us by email at [ info@ppi2pass.com](mailto:info@ppi2pass.com) or use our [**Contact Us**](https://ppi2pass.com/contact-us) tool.

You may also call us at 1-650-593-9119 or send a letter to:

PPI Attn: Privacy Policy  
1250 Fifth Avenue  
Belmont, CA 94002

Effective Date: March 7, 2018
